<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ave Maria on</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/tags/ave-maria/</link><description>Recent content in Ave Maria on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-AU</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:53:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christinetham.github.io/tags/ave-maria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov) – Logic Pro X, EWQL</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</guid><description>The arrangement is Finale2014a performance converted to MIDI, loaded to Logic Pro X, and revoiced using the EWQL Symphony Orchestra Gold. Final mastering in Logic Pro X and Ozone 5.</description></item><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov) – Finale/GPO4</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-finale/gpo4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:43:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-finale/gpo4/</guid><description>The full name of this piece is Неизвестный автор XVI в. (Ave Maria). Often (incorrectly) ascribed to Guilio Caccini, this work was actually composed by Vladimir Fyodorovich Vavilov (Влади́мир Фёдорович Вави́лов) in 1970 and featured in his album “Lute music of the XVI-XVII cent.” (Лютневая музыка 16-17 веков) released on the Melodiya label. I have transcribed the melody by listening to the original recording, then harmonised, added counterpoint and arranged it in 12 parts for strings and woodwinds.</description></item><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 06:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov/</guid><description>Incorrectly ascribed to Guilio Caccini, this work was actually composed by Vladimir Fyodorovich Vavilov (Влади́мир Фёдорович Вави́лов) in 1970 and featured in his album “Lute music of the XVI-XVII cent.” (Лютневая музыка 16-17 веков) released on the Melodiya label.
I listened to the original recording, transcribed it to Notion, then rearranged it for woodwinds, strings and harp, voiced using the EWQL Symphonic Orchestra.</description></item></channel></rss>