<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EWQL on</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/tags/ewql/</link><description>Recent content in EWQL on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-AU</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 07:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christinetham.github.io/tags/ewql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Olhos De Gato (orchestral arrangement)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/olhos-de-gato-orchestral-arrangement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 07:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/olhos-de-gato-orchestral-arrangement/</guid><description>To celebrate the completion of the Jazz Improvisation class I am taking, I have arranged Olhos de Gato, by Carla Bley (one of the pieces studied in class) for orchestra. I have created a string backing for the melody, then added the melody from “Memories of Tomorrow” (another piece studied in class) as a counterpoint, and also my own melody as a further counterpoint. Finally, I created a new ending, based on a descending harmonic progression.</description></item><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov) – Logic Pro X, EWQL</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</guid><description>The arrangement is Finale2014a performance converted to MIDI, loaded to Logic Pro X, and revoiced using the EWQL Symphony Orchestra Gold. Final mastering in Logic Pro X and Ozone 5.</description></item><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 06:06:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/ave-maria-vavilov/</guid><description>Incorrectly ascribed to Guilio Caccini, this work was actually composed by Vladimir Fyodorovich Vavilov (Влади́мир Фёдорович Вави́лов) in 1970 and featured in his album “Lute music of the XVI-XVII cent.” (Лютневая музыка 16-17 веков) released on the Melodiya label.
I listened to the original recording, transcribed it to Notion, then rearranged it for woodwinds, strings and harp, voiced using the EWQL Symphonic Orchestra.</description></item><item><title>Winter Music</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/winter-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 06:03:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/winter-music/</guid><description> Music composed by Roger Eno and included in “Between Tides” album. Transcribed and orchestrated using Notion and EWQL Symphonic Orchestra Gold.</description></item><item><title>Brandenburg Concerto No.5 in D major, BWV 1050 – I. Allegro [solo instruments]</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/brandenburg-concerto-no.5-in-d-major-bwv-1050-i.-allegro-solo-instruments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 06:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/brandenburg-concerto-no.5-in-d-major-bwv-1050-i.-allegro-solo-instruments/</guid><description> Reorchestrated using solo string instruments for a more authentic Baroque feel and changed harpsichord to EWQL. Performed by Finale 2014a (Baroque HP). Orchestrated using mixture of EWQL Symphonic Orchestra Gold and Garritan Personal Orchestra 4. MIDI downloaded from IMSLP (attributed to Michel Rondeau with Copyright Creative Commons Attribution 3.0, part of the Werner Icking Music Collection.)</description></item><item><title>Babylon 5 opening theme</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/babylon-5-opening-theme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 05:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/babylon-5-opening-theme/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>