<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Background on</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/</link><description>Recent content in Background on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-AU</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/introduction/</guid><description>Hi there!
I live in Sydney, and love cycling, photography, music, and travel (not necessarily in those order). On this website, I will share mainly my personal photos and thoughts.</description></item><item><title>My Great Grandfather</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/my-great-grandfather/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/my-great-grandfather/</guid><description>My great grandfather was Tam Yong (father of towkay Tan Yee Man), Kapitan China of Seremban. According to Wikipedia:
Kapitan Cina, also spelled Kapitan China or Capitan China (English: Captain of the Chinese; Chinese: 華人甲必丹; pinyin: Huárén Jiǎbìdān; Dutch: Kapitein der Chinezen), was a high-ranking government position in the civil administration of colonial Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, Borneo and the Philippines. Office holders exercised varying degrees of power and influence: from near-sovereign political and legal jurisdiction over local Chinese communities, to ceremonial precedence for community leaders.</description></item><item><title>The Tham (譚) surname</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/tham-surname/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 14:41:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/about/background/tham-surname/</guid><description>The surname Tham (譚) is pronounced and romanised differently in different languages and dialects:
Tan (Hokkien Chinese and Mandarin Chinese) Tan (Japanese) Dam (Korean) Đàm (Vietnamese) Tam (Cantonese Chinese and Hakka Chinese) Tham (Hokkien Chinese and Teochew Chinese) Ham, Hom, Hum, Tom, Thom (Toisanese Chinese) The standard Hanyu Pinyin romanisation is Tan and it is pronounced Taam4 (Jyutping romanisation) in Cantonese.
According to Wikipedia, it is the 56th most common Chinese surname.</description></item></channel></rss>