<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-AU</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 07:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christham.net/christham-hugo/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cinema Paradiso (string Orchestra)</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/cinema-paradiso-string-orchestra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 07:19:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/cinema-paradiso-string-orchestra/</guid><description>In memory of Ennio Morricone, a string orchestra arrangement of Cinema Paradiso, transcribed by me into Finale.</description></item><item><title>Bach – Prelude No 1 in C major WTC1</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/bach-prelude-no-1-in-c-major-wtc1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 07:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/bach-prelude-no-1-in-c-major-wtc1/</guid><description>First piano recording done using a metronome - Bach&amp;rsquo;s Prelude No 1. I have decided to play it at a slower tempo than usual, to highlight each note and to introduce micro rhythms within the bar and across bars. The piano is a virtual Bosendorfer 290 recorded at EastWest Studios, and the piece was played on a Kawai MP10 and then processed using Logic Pro X, QL Spaces and iZotope Ozone 8.</description></item><item><title>Bach - Adagio from Concerto for solo keyboard No. 3 in D minor</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/bach-adagio-from-concerto-for-solo-keyboard-no.-3-in-d-minor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 07:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/bach-adagio-from-concerto-for-solo-keyboard-no.-3-in-d-minor/</guid><description>This is the second movement from J S Bach&amp;rsquo;s arrangement of Alessandro Marcello&amp;rsquo;s Oboe Concerto BWV 974 (BC L194). It is not often performed, but after hearing Glenn Gould&amp;rsquo;s amazing rendition of it, I had to learn how to play it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t rely on the metronome as i wanted the freedom of varying the tempo, but I visually aligned to the target tempo at the start so the first 10 bars or so are pretty on the beat, after that &amp;hellip; Recorded using a Kawai MP10.</description></item><item><title>Winter Music (electronic 115bpm)</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/winter-music-electronic-115bpm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/winter-music-electronic-115bpm/</guid><description>My first project in Maschine 3 – a dance arrangement of Roger Eno’s track from Between Tides album, with the speed doubled to 115bpm and the Focus kit from Prismatic Bliss.</description></item><item><title>Adagio (2nd movement) from Oboe Concerto in D minor (Alessandro Marcello)</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/adagio-2nd-movement-from-oboe-concerto-in-d-minor-alessandro-marcello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/adagio-2nd-movement-from-oboe-concerto-in-d-minor-alessandro-marcello/</guid><description>My first arrangement for 2018! This is a synth arrangement of the slow movement from Alessandro Marcello&amp;rsquo;s beautiful Oboe Concerto in D minor, op. 1 using Logic Pro native instruments. It is a beautiful and tranquil piece that is perhaps not well known (even though JS Bach transcribed it for harpsichord).</description></item><item><title>A Twin Peaks dream</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/a-twin-peaks-dream/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 06:12:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/a-twin-peaks-dream/</guid><description>Inspired by watching Twin Peaks The Return, here is a short electronic track, done in Logic Pro X and Native Instruments Komplete 11. All sounds are created by me using a combination of Monark, Absynth, Massive and Reaktor.</description></item><item><title>Olhos De Gato (orchestral arrangement)</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/olhos-de-gato-orchestral-arrangement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 07:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/olhos-de-gato-orchestral-arrangement/</guid><description>To celebrate the completion of the Jazz Improvisation class I am taking, I have arranged Olhos de Gato, by Carla Bley (one of the pieces studied in class) for orchestra. I have created a string backing for the melody, then added the melody from “Memories of Tomorrow” (another piece studied in class) as a counterpoint, and also my own melody as a further counterpoint. Finally, I created a new ending, based on a descending harmonic progression.</description></item><item><title>500 Miles High</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/500-miles-high/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 05:49:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/500-miles-high/</guid><description>I took the lead sheet and expanded it to four parts for string quartet, with each instrument (apart from cello) taking turns to play the melody, with the other instruments either providing counterpoint or harmony.</description></item><item><title>Memories of Tomorrow</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/memories-of-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 05:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/memories-of-tomorrow/</guid><description>I took the original lead sheet provided in the assignment, then expanded to four parts that are polyrhythmic as well as polyphonic (based on Latin rhythms). I also added separate improvisations for piano and flute. Finally, I added open-voiced string harmonisation in the final section to indicate the guide tones and basis for future improvisation.</description></item><item><title>Ave Maria (Vavilov) – Logic Pro X, EWQL</title><link>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 06:53:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christham.net/christham-hugo/blog/ave-maria-vavilov-logic-pro-x-ewql/</guid><description>The arrangement is Finale2014a performance converted to MIDI, loaded to Logic Pro X, and revoiced using the EWQL Symphony Orchestra Gold. Final mastering in Logic Pro X and Ozone 5.</description></item></channel></rss>