<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-AU</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christinetham.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sunday Dose Breakfast</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/sunday-dose-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/sunday-dose-breakfast/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled by the photo of me wearing cycling clothes. I actually woke up late, missed the ride, and ended up cycling indoors. But I decided to join the team (Zeal of Zebras) for post ride breakfast.</description></item><item><title>How to Draw Almost Every Day</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/how-to-draw-almost-every-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 06:10:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/how-to-draw-almost-every-day/</guid><description>I am using COPIC markers to replicate the drawings in the book.
This is what Book Depository says about it:
The perfect book for budding artists, How to Draw Almost Every Day challenges and inspires you to draw one simple illustration each day of the year.
Don&amp;rsquo;t let your artistic aspirations come to an end before they start! Everyone wants to draw stylish, evocative pictures, but between busy schedules, not knowing basic techniques, and simply feeling like their art isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;good enough,&amp;rdquo; many people quickly give up on learning to draw.</description></item><item><title>Mayfield Garden</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/mayfield-garden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/mayfield-garden/</guid><description>Mayfield was established in 1984 by the Hawkins family, initially as a sheep farm. The heart of our property has been gradually transformed – with the help of talented local landscapers and tradespeople – from bare paddocks into one of the largest, privately owned cool climate gardens in the world.
Mayfield has been inspired by the magnificent gardens of Europe. Owned by the Hawkins family, Mayfield Garden (open 363 days of the year) and The Hawkins’ Family Garden, together, cover more than 64 hectares (160 acres).</description></item><item><title>Kon Loh Mee recipe</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/kon-loh-mee-recipe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 05:42:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/kon-loh-mee-recipe/</guid><description>“Kon Loh Mee” or dry stirred noodles, is a popular Malaysian hawker dish, typically served with a combination of BBQ pork (“char siu”) and wantan, although variations exist such as minced meat (like an Asian version of spaghetti bolognese), roasted/steamed chicken and vegetarian options.
The noodles are usually thin egg noodles and the sauce tends to be thick, dark, slightly sweet. As a child, my mum sometimes buy them from a hawker stall when she goes to the market in the early morning, so by the time we kids get up, we are treated a beautiful kon loh mee as a breakfast!</description></item><item><title>Cinema Paradiso (string Orchestra)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/cinema-paradiso-string-orchestra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 07:19:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/cinema-paradiso-string-orchestra/</guid><description>In memory of Ennio Morricone, a string orchestra arrangement of Cinema Paradiso, transcribed by me into Finale.</description></item><item><title>Bach – Prelude No 1 in C major WTC1</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/bach-prelude-no-1-in-c-major-wtc1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 07:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/bach-prelude-no-1-in-c-major-wtc1/</guid><description>First piano recording done using a metronome - Bach&amp;rsquo;s Prelude No 1. I have decided to play it at a slower tempo than usual, to highlight each note and to introduce micro rhythms within the bar and across bars. The piano is a virtual Bosendorfer 290 recorded at EastWest Studios, and the piece was played on a Kawai MP10 and then processed using Logic Pro X, QL Spaces and iZotope Ozone 8.</description></item><item><title>Bach - Adagio from Concerto for solo keyboard No. 3 in D minor</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/bach-adagio-from-concerto-for-solo-keyboard-no.-3-in-d-minor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 07:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/bach-adagio-from-concerto-for-solo-keyboard-no.-3-in-d-minor/</guid><description>This is the second movement from J S Bach&amp;rsquo;s arrangement of Alessandro Marcello&amp;rsquo;s Oboe Concerto BWV 974 (BC L194). It is not often performed, but after hearing Glenn Gould&amp;rsquo;s amazing rendition of it, I had to learn how to play it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t rely on the metronome as i wanted the freedom of varying the tempo, but I visually aligned to the target tempo at the start so the first 10 bars or so are pretty on the beat, after that &amp;hellip; Recorded using a Kawai MP10.</description></item><item><title>My new bike – Specialized Ruby Expert :-)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/my-new-bike/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 13:37:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/my-new-bike/</guid><description>I have finally decided to replace my commuter bike (“Cadel” – my self-built bike based on an Olmo Kurva frame, Shimano Ultegra groupset, DuraAce wheels, 3T stem, handlebar and seat post and finzi:k saddle). The bike is approaching 7 years old (I completed the build on the day Cadel Evans won the Tour of France, hence the name). Although the bike still works, I noticed the steering has become less confident, particularly braking down a descent, so it was probably time for a change.</description></item><item><title>Winter Music (electronic 115bpm)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/winter-music-electronic-115bpm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/winter-music-electronic-115bpm/</guid><description>My first project in Maschine 3 – a dance arrangement of Roger Eno’s track from Between Tides album, with the speed doubled to 115bpm and the Focus kit from Prismatic Bliss.</description></item><item><title>Adagio (2nd movement) from Oboe Concerto in D minor (Alessandro Marcello)</title><link>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/adagio-2nd-movement-from-oboe-concerto-in-d-minor-alessandro-marcello/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:14:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christinetham.github.io/blog/adagio-2nd-movement-from-oboe-concerto-in-d-minor-alessandro-marcello/</guid><description>My first arrangement for 2018! This is a synth arrangement of the slow movement from Alessandro Marcello&amp;rsquo;s beautiful Oboe Concerto in D minor, op. 1 using Logic Pro native instruments. It is a beautiful and tranquil piece that is perhaps not well known (even though JS Bach transcribed it for harpsichord).</description></item></channel></rss>